The AddTorque function is similar to
AddTorque 関数は AddForce に似ていますが、
AddForce, but the force works by rotating
違いとして、 ゲームオブジェクトを定まった軸の周りに
the game object around a defined axis.
回転させることで力が働きます。
AddTorque has two components,
AddTorque には二つのコンポーネントがあり、
the second being optional. The first is
二つめは必須ではありません。一つめは
a vector that defines the axis around
トルクを適用すべき軸および
which the torque will be applied
適用するトルクの大きさを定義する
and the magnitude of the torque applied.
ベクトルです。
In this example our power cube
このサンプルでは powerCube は
has this script attached.
このスクリプトがアタッチされています。
We are using the AddTorque function
AddTorque 関数を使用していて
and specifying that transform.up,
オブジェクトの上方向である
the local up direction of the object,
Transform.up が
will be the axis to add torque to.
トルクを加えるべき軸であることを示します。
Because Unity uses the left-hand screw rule
Unity は左手系であるため
torque will be added around this axis
この図で示すように
as shown in this diagram.
トルクはこの軸周りに加えられます。
Try for yourself by making a thumbs-up
自身で試すために、親指を立てて
gesture with your left hand. Then imagine
左手系の手の形を作ってみてください。
that the torque is added in the direction
手のひらで指が曲がっている方向に
that your fingers are curled in to your palm.
トルクが加えられていると想像して下さい。
Here we are simply multiplying by the
ここでは
variable H, which is a variable used
水平軸からの入力変数 h に amount 変数を掛け算して、
to get input from the horizontal axis,
さらにデルタ時間を
multiplied by the amount variable over time.
掛け算します。
On the other AddTorque line we are applying
もうひとつの AddTorque の行には transform.right 軸に
it to the transform.right axis.
、すなわちオブジェクトの X 軸に
The local X axis of the object.
適用しています。
Let's see this in action.
これを実際に動かしてみましょう。
When I press the horizontal keys
Horizontal の キーを押下すると
I can apply torque and as you can see
トルクを加えることが出来て、みてのとおり
once the torque is applied and I let go of
トルクを加えたあとに、キーを話すと、
the key the inertia will
初速はそのまま継続するのは
keep going because this is part of
これが物理シミュレーション
the physics simulation.
であるためです。
Similarly I can apply it to the X axis
同様にして X 軸に適用して
and because this is local it will spin
そしてこれはローカル座標であるため
around that axis depending on wherever
どこにあろうとも軸を中心に
it happens to be.
回ります。
You should also keep in mind that the angular
Rigidbody の Angular Drag  コンポーネントにより
drag component of the rigidbody
オブジェクトにどれぐらいの量だけトルクが
would define how effective the torque is
適用されているか
when applied to the object.
定義されます。
For example I can apply a lot of torque
例えば、たくさんのトルクを
around this axis, leave it running under
この軸に適用して、初速のまま動かすことが出来ますが、
inertia, but when I increase angular drag
Angular Drag を増加させると
it becomes a lot harder to get that object
Angular Drag の影響でオブジェクトが動くのが
moving because of the angular drag.
難しくなってきます。
Whereas if we have no angular drag
これに対して Angular Drag がまったくない場合、
it's easy to keep the object spinning
オブジェクトを特定の方向にスピンし続けるのは
in a particular direction because there's
容易なことであり、加わる抵抗（Drag）はきわめて
very little drag slowing it down.
僅かです。
The second parameter is an optional
二つめのパラメータは必須でないものであり、
parameter used to effect the type of
適用される力のタイプに
force that's going to be applied.
影響があります。
If this is left out it will default to
もし何も入れなかった倍、
the type Force.
タイプはデフォルトの Force となります。
This is used for continuous changes
これは継続的な変更に用いられ
that are effected by mass.
重量（Mass）により影響を受けます。
Acceleration is for continuous changes
Acceleration は重量により影響を受けない
that aren't effected by mass.
継続的な変更に使用されます。
Impulse is for an instant change that
Impulse は重量に影響される瞬間的な変化
is effected by mass.
に使用されます。
And Velocity Change is for an instant
Velocity Change は重量に影響されない
change that isn't effected by mass.
瞬間的な変更に使用されます。
Let's see the effect of adding this to our script.
これをスクリプトに追加することでの影響をみてみましょう。
Now when rotating the cube using our torque
次にトルクを使用してキューブを回転させるとき、
when I press the opposite key to apply
反対のキーを押して
torque in the other direction it responds
逆方向にトルクを適用したとき、
far more quickly.
明らかに速く反応します。
So it's worth always considering the type
このことから、トルクを追加するときに加える力のタイプを
of force that you're applying when adding torque.
考慮するのは重要なことです。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)